--=圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hd.cnscg.com/=--
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
协调: 影子
翻译: 卡夫横 叉烧酥 Mabb 戴蜀
校对: 白咪咪 爱鼠影
Kate给你留了个带有地图的瓶子
Kate leaves you a bottle with a map on it,
却带我们来到了... 纽约中央车站?
and this is where it leads us... Grand Central Station?
这肯定有我认识的东西 Moz
It's something I'd recognize, Moz.
特别的东西
Something significant.
特别的东西?
Significant?
这是纽约中央车站啊!
Grand Central Station!
是熟悉的东西
Something familiar.
她本可以指引我们到任何地方
She could have sent us anywhere,
结果却是可以去任何地方的车站?
so she sends us to a place that leads everywhere?
Moz 看
Moz.
这有一家很好的牡蛎餐厅
You know, there's a great oyster bar in there.
我觉得那里面有东西
Hey, I think there's something in here.
"X"标记地点... 又一次吗?
"X" marks the spot... again?
Kate喜欢经典
Kate likes the classics.
"亲爱的Neal 听说你在找我
"Dear Neal, heard you're looking for me.
我希望我能解释 但是时间不允许
Wish I could explain more, but time is not on our side,
但是你不要再找我了
but you need to stop looking.
我们曾经深爱过 但一切都结束了
No one can deny what we have, but it's over.
请放手向前
Please move on.
Kate敬上"
Kate."
留了这么多密码 就说了一句"放手向前"
All this for "move on".
太矛盾了
Oddly bipolar.
我宁愿去吃点牡蛎
I'd rather have some oysters.
- 嗨  - 嗨
- Hey.  - Hey.
周末过得怎样?
Have a good weekend?
哦 没什么刺激的
Ah, nothing too exciting.
我去了趟公园
I went to the park.
太棒了 很高兴你出去走走了
Oh, great. Glad you're getting out.
要咖啡吗?
Coffee?
没时间喝咖啡了 有个画作失窃案
Love to. No time. Got a stolen painting.
这可是June买的意大利烘焙
It's June's Italian roast.
这是...
It's...
豪斯腾伯格的作品
Haustenberg.
豪斯腾伯格啊...
Haustenberg, well...
在博物馆失窃的吗?
is it a museum heist?
不 是在家里
No. Residential robbery.
我想见见
I'd like to meet the person
把豪斯腾伯格的画挂在墙上的人
who keeps a Haustenberg over their mantel.
大爱豪斯滕伯格 哪一幅画作被偷了?
Love Haustenberg. Which one of his paintings is stolen?
这幅画叫"戴金挂坠的女孩'
This one is called "Young girl with a locket".
没照片吗?
No photograph?
没有 但我敢肯定这幅画上
No, but I bet you it's a painting
画着个带金挂坠的女孩
of a young girl wearing a locket.
你的推理能力我可不敢恭维
You don't get enough credit for your deductive skills.
这幅画价值超过两百万美元
It's worth $2 million and change.
真厉害
That's nice.
豪斯腾伯格的画很少见
Haustenbergs are rare.
他的作品只有很少在战争后流出了匈牙利
Not many of his works made it out of Hungary after the war.
是啊 稀少所以才值钱... 非常的值钱
Yeah. Rare can make it valuable... very valuable.
你这么看着我干吗?
What are you looking at me for?
为什么这么问?
Why do you think?
我没偷
I didn't steal it.
我知道你没偷
I know you didn't steal it,
但是你喜欢画作
but you like paintings.
我担心如果我们找到了它
I'm worried that if we find it,
会对你产生巨大的诱惑
it may be too much temptation for you.
我会抵制诱惑
I can handle temptation.
你能盯着前面的路吗?
Do you want to keep your eyes on the road?
这是辆福特金牛座 可以自动刹车的
This is a Taurus. Car can take care of itself.
我要盯着你
I'm keeping my eyes on you.
好吧 随你 看路也很重要
Good, good. The road is important, too.
我看着的 抱歉
I see the road. Sorry about that.
别 别道歉 那是... 他停下的错
No. Don't apologize. That was... he stopped.
你知道我没偷 你查看了我的脚铐记录?
You know I didn't steal it. You checked my anklet?
我一直在查看记录
I always check your anklet.
我每天对着地图检查
I pull a map up on you every day
那我就能知道你每天去了哪
so I can see exactly where you've been.
纽约中央车站有什么有趣的东西吗?
What was so interesting about Grand Central Station?
牡蛎餐厅啊... 城里最好的了
Oyster bar... it's the best in town.
我待在我的两公里活动范围内
I stayed within my two-mile radius.
我在想 你的活动范围是不是太大了
I wonder if we've been a little too generous on that.
天啊
Oh, yeah.
怎么 你还不高兴了?
What, are you gonna sulk now?
你不信任我
You don't trust me.
里根(美国总统)说过什么?
What did Reagan say?
"信任他 但要核查"
"Trust, but verify."
还有句出自苏联秘密警察的名言
That was also the motto of the Soviet secret police.
同志们 学着适应吧
Get used to it, comrade.
看路!
Eyes! Road!
我们还是专注办案吧
Let's just recover the painting.
是啊 还有开车
Yeah, and drive.
联邦调查局都出动了... 你们很看重这事啊?
Wow, so, the FBI... you're really taking this seriously, huh?
是的
We are.
你是房子的主人吗?
Are you the homeowner?
是的
Yes.
这样啊
Yeah.
我父母去世了 我已经21岁了 还有我被盗了
My parents are dead, I'm over 21, and I was robbed.
还有什么问题吗?
Any other questions?
画上过保险吗?
Was the painting insured?
没有
No.
它可值两百六十万啊
It's worth $2.6 million.
它原来在那
That's where it was.
星期二我有课
Tuesdays I have classes.
老师提前下了课
Uh, the instructor let us out early.
我进家门 看见有个... 怪物在那
I came in here, and there was this... monster here,
他把我按在墙上
and he shoved me up against the wall.
他伤到你了吗?
He hurt you?
是的
Yeah.
我一拳打在他脸上
I hit him in the face,
他说 我再打他 就杀了我
and he said if I did it again, he would kill me.
然后呢?
What did you do?
我又打了他
I hit him again.
你有画的照片吗?
Do you have a photo of the painting?
你的报告上只有文字描述
Your report only had a description.
有的
Yeah. Yeah.
怎么了?
Can I help you?
没事 Gary 他们是联邦调查局的
Oh, it's okay, Gary. It's the FBI.
他们来问画的事情
They're here about the painting.
哦 这样啊
Oh, of course.
谢谢你们尽快赶来
Thank you for coming so quickly.
应该的 画被盗的时候你在场吗?
Sure, sure. Were you there when it happened?
没 我在工作呢
No. I was at work at the time.
抱歉无法帮你们了
Wish I could be more help.
没关系
Great.
这个窃贼是内部人吧?
We looking at an inside job?
小偷了解她的行程 除了画什么都没拿
Thief knew her schedule. Nothing else was taken.
- 我去问问  - 我去
- I'd go with that.  - I'd go with that, too.
你去看Julianna拿的那张照片
Help Julianna with that photo.
Gary 我有几个问题
Gary, I have a few questions.
Gary是你的...?
Gary's your, um...?
- 叔叔  - 叔叔啊
- Uncle.  - Uncle.
这张行吗?
Will that do?
天啊
Oh, my goodness.
那是我奶奶 画在她后面
That's my grandmother. That's the painting behind her.
你们长得很像啊
Could be your twin.
我当这是夸我了
I'll take that as a compliment.
我继承了她的名字 她把我养大
I was named after her. She raised me.
她去世后 她把房子留给了我...
When she died, she left me the house...
还有那幅画
and the painting.
你叔叔Gary怎么想?
What did uncle Gary think of that?
你看上去不像是联邦探员啊
You don't look like an FBI agent.
我也当这是夸我了
I'll take that as a compliment.
联邦探员是什么样?
What's an FBI agent look like?
他这样
Him.
拿到照片了吗?
You got the photo?
我们走吧
Let's go.
妙警贼探 第一季第5集
我从没见过那么快申请律师了的
I've never seen a guy lawyer up that fast.
我就了解到他在华尔街当股票交易师
I've got that he's a stock trader on Wall Street
然后他就让我
and that his attorney
问他的律师了
will answer any further questions I might have.
那么 Gary叔叔给小偷提供了情报
So, uncle Gary tips off the thief,
从其中分成
splits the take.
更可能是他欠了别人钱
More likely uncle Gary owes money to somebody,
然后他受够了看着两百万美元的画
and he got tired of staring at 2 million bucks
挂在墙上
hanging on the wall.
他既然什么都不肯定说 我们要来点强制手段
Now he shuts up, and we do this the hard way.
什么强制手段?
The hard way?
我们只需要知道跟他合作的那个小偷叫什么 是吧?
All we need from Gary is the name of the guy he's working with, right?
- 是的  - 那为什么不让我跟他谈谈?
- Right.  - So, why don't I talk to him?
- 你?  - 是啊
- You?  - Yeah.
好... 好吧 我再说一遍
O... Okay, let me rephrase that.
因为我只是个顾问
Since I am a consultant
不是严格意义上的联邦调查局的...
and not technically an employee of the FBI...
是假释试用期的顾问
A consultant on a tenuous probation.
我从不敢忘
As I'm constantly reminded.
我跟他谈话有什么不合法的地方吗?
Is there anything illegal about me talking to him?
- 不准威胁他  - 没这个打算
- You can't threaten him.  - Don't plan to.
不准骗他
Or lie to him.
好吧
All right.
好吧 不骗他
All right. No lying.
我只是要问他名字
I'm just gonna ask him for the name.
告诉我 Gary
Tell me, Gary,
Julianna知道你帮别人偷了那幅画吗?
Does Julianna know you helped steal the painting?
你不能在这
You can't be here.
我的律师说得很清楚
My lawyer was very clear.
首先 雇律师显得你有罪
First of all, hiring a lawyer makes you look guilty.
律师明确告诉我 不能跟联邦调查局的人讲话
He told me specifically not to talk to the FBI.
我看上去像联邦探员吗?
Do I look like an FBI agent?
你是谁?
Who are you?
好好想想 Gary
Think hard, Gary.
他派你来的?
Did he send you?
你觉得呢?
What do you think?
天啊 我就知道会这样
God, I knew this would happen.
难道整件事都是个圈套?
What, that whole thing at the house was a setup?
怎么会出错的?
How'd it go wrong?
Julianna不该在那
Julianna wasn't supposed to be there.
现在她是个目击证人
Now she's a witness.
这不关我的事 她提前下课了
It wasn't my fault. Her class got out early.
请别伤害她
Please don't hurt her.
你要说服的不是我
It's not me you need to convince.
告诉他...
Tell him...
告诉他 我保证她不会是个麻烦
tell him I'll make sure she doesn't cause any trouble.
她已经对画师描述罪犯长相了
She's ready to sit with a sketch artist.
这种情况让他很难
This is the kind of thing that makes it much harder for him
把画卖掉
to sell the painting.
这样... 好吗?
How about... here?
我交保证金怎么样?
How about a good-faith payment?
这有三百 我身上就这么多
Here. Here's $300. That's all I got.
才三百
$300.
Gary啊
Gary.
好吧 你是对的
All right, you're right. You're right.
我给他开张支票吧
I can write him a check.
这个可以
That could work.
他给你开了张个人支票
He wrote you a personal check
给偷了他母亲的画的人
to the guy he helped steal his mother's painting.
他执意这么做
He was very insistent.
没有威胁 没有撒谎
No threats. No lies.
都是他自愿坦白的
I let him do all the talking.
我把这叫做"灰色地带"
I'm calling this a "gray area".
是Gerard Dorsett啊
Oh. Gerard Dorsett.
- 你知道他?  - 是啊
- You know him?  - Yeah.
是啊 他是个... 坏蛋
Yeah, he's a... bad guy.
我知道
So I figured.
Julianna怎么办?
Hey, what about Julianna?
他知道了她跟我们谈过话...
He figures out she's talking to us...
让我们在坏事发生前抓住这混蛋
Let's catch the bastard before that happens.
是啊 我们找到他了
Yeah, we got him.
而且已经监视他两天了
We've been sitting on him for two days.
他们跑遍了曼哈顿的所有高级画廊
They've gone to every high-end gallery in Manhattan
要出手那幅豪斯滕伯格的画
offering the Haustenberg.
那个人是谁?
Who's that?
那个大块头? 他是Joshua
The big guy? Joshua.
退役军人 偷走画的人就是他
Ex-military, the muscle who stole the painting.
Julianna说打了他一拳 还真不是开玩笑的
Julianna wasn't kidding about the punch.
那女孩可够有劲的
Girl has an arm.
另一个家伙是Dorsett 法国移民
And the other guy is Dorsett, French expat.
除了勒索股票经纪人 他还对什么事感兴趣?
What's he into, besides shaking down stockbrokers?
放高利贷
High-end loan-sharking,
但说他是放高利贷的人
although calling him a loan shark
就像说俄狄浦斯(希腊神话中弑父娶母的人)是妈妈的乖宝宝一样
is like calling Oedipus a mama's boy.
他用大笔公款放高利贷
He makes questionable loans with big corporate money.
不还钱的话 他就去烧了你的办公室
Get behind on your payment, he'll firebomb your office.
不过好消息是 你明天就会见到他
But the good news is, you get to meet him tomorrow.
你怎么安排的?
How'd you arrange that?
是我安排的
I set it up.
Neal 这是Taryn Vandersant
Neal, this is Taryn Vandersant.
她是Lambert画廊的顾客
She's a buyer at the Lambert gallery
而且还很热心地要帮我们解决这个案子
and is nice enough to help us out on this one.
我让Dorsett相信 我这里有一位有钱的买家
I convinced Dorsett I have a wealthy client
对他手里的画很感兴趣
who's very interested in the painting.
他要价多少?
How much is he asking?
十万美金
$100,000.
Neal 我们已经安排好
We've arranged to have the exchange happen
在画廊进行交易了
at the gallery, Neal.
Jones 咱们得好好准备一下
Jones, let's get a prep.
这一定会很有趣的
This should be fun.
怎么了?
What?
你有没有遇到过哪个女人对你不...
Have you ever met a woman who didn't...
有啊 Brittni... Brittni Nichole...
Brittni... Brittni Nichole...
在二年级的时候
in second grade.
那时候我有牙缝
I had a gap in my teeth.
周五中午 在这里见面
Kate喜欢经典的东西
Kate loves the classics.
那真的就是一大包要洗的衣服啊
That's a big load of laundry.
是啊 这包东西刚卖了十二万美金
Yeah. It just sold for $120,000.
什么?
What?
- 嘿 别碰!  - 怎么了?
- Hey, hey!  - What?
你永远不能给艺术品标价
Can't put a price on art.
确实不能 所以我才觉得以二百六十万的价格
No, you can't, which is why I think $2.6 million
卖豪斯滕伯格的画也太贵了
is a little steep for the Haustenberg.
你不是特别喜欢豪斯滕伯格的作品吧?
You're not a fan of Haustenberg?
呃 我不知道
Uh, I don't know.
对于我来说 他的画有点太卡通了
It's a little cartoony for my taste.
你... 你真是个俗人
You're... you're a philistine.
好吧 好吧
Yeah, yeah.
我... 我才是疯子
I... I'm the crazy one.
- 都装好了吗?  - 装好了
- You all set?  - All set.
咱们去装窃听器吧
Well, let's get wired.
十万现金... 那可是不少钱呢
100 grand in cash... that's a lot of money.
有诱惑力吗?
Tempted?
你为什么这么想?
Why would you think that?
Peter警告我小心你
Peter warned me about you.
警告你?
Warned you?
听起来挺危险的嘛
Sounds ominous.
- 有吗?  - 有啊
- Does it?  - Yeah.
你是刚从监狱里出来吗?
Is it true you just got out of prison?
我看起来像是刚从监狱里出来的吗?
Do I look like I just got out of prison?
他说了你会这样的
He said you'd do that.
哪样?
What?
反问
Redirect.
是 我是刚从监狱里出来
Yes, I just got out of prison,
也是Peter把我送进去的
yes, Peter is the guy who put me there,
而且没错...
and, yes...
这钱确实很诱惑
I'm tempted.
你真的是为了一个女孩才越狱的吗?
Is it true you escaped for a girl?
有人说我个浪漫的人
Some people think I'm a romantic.
她这么觉得吗?
Did she?
我以后再告诉你
I'll let you know.
我们看见Dorsett穿过了第20街
We got Dorsett crossing 20th.
把画面切过去
Let's get a camera on that.
看到了
Okay.
他们正在往画廊走
They're approaching the gallery.
第一分队盯紧点
Team one has the eye.
很高兴再次见到你
Good to see you again.
我也很高兴见到您
Good to see you.
我电话里说的就是他 Devore先生
As I said on the phone, this is Mr. Devore.
叫我George就好
Call me George.
这画比我想象的小啊
It's smaller than I expected.
你见过"蒙娜丽莎"吗? 那幅画更小
Have you seen the "Mona Lisa"? It's tiny.
我能看看钱在哪里吗?
Could I see the money, please?
我来做鉴定吧
I'd like to authenticate it.
你们两个认识很久了?
So, you two have known each other for a long time?
我们认识了 我都不记得了 有多久了?
We've been friends for, I don't know, how long's it been?
很多年了
Years.
两位才貌出众 一定不只是朋友吧
Beautiful people are never just friends.
George有女朋友
George has a girlfriend.
又一次证明了一夫一妻制是美人的不幸
Again, monogamy is the great casualty of beauty.
不一定吧
Not always.
真的
Please.
我们用"蝴蝶"形容
We use the expression "butterfly"
到处拈花惹草的男人
for a man who flits from flower to flower.
您这样一表人才 肯定在这方面很成功吧
A man such as yourself could be quite a successful butterfly.
我们觉得蝴蝶是一种脆弱的生物
We consider butterflies weak, delicate creatures.
是啊 但是蝴蝶扇一扇翅膀 就能引起一场飓风呢
Yes, but flap their wings, and they can set off hurricanes.
你真会说话 可以写本书了
That's beautiful. You should write a book.
- 我们...  - 请把门关上
- Can we...  - Close the doors, please.
我也有个女朋友
I have a girlfriend myself.
她对你忠诚吗?
Is she faithful?
她也是法国人 我尽量不去想这个问题
She's French. I try not to think about it.
Brigitte昨晚刚到这里
Brigitte arrived last night,
我不应该让她一个人在陌生的城市里待太久
and I shouldn't leave her alone in a new town for long.
我们可不可以快点
Perhaps we could hurry.
当然 请关下灯
Of course. Lights, please.
荧光下 画面上显示出来了镉绿色和石青蓝色
I've got fluorescing cadmium green and azurite blue.
证明这幅画的创作时间早于六十年代
That puts the paint composition pre-1960.
你能不能解释一下
Perhaps you can explain
外面的人为什么互相打暗号
why there are people signaling each other outside.
我们过去吗?
You want us to go?
现在还不行 太冒险了
Not yet. We can't risk it.
他们是什么人?
Who are they?
要是你把联邦调查局的人引来这里...
If you brought the FBI into this...
我才没有!
It was not me!
我告诉你低调行事
I told you to keep a low profile.
你们太不小心了
You were careless.
你们带着这幅画满城招摇
You've been flashing this painting all over town.
他们当然是跟着你们来的
They followed you here.
这里面肯定有问题
Something is not right here.
当然有问题
Damn right it's not.
我浪费了时间和精力 钱我拿走了
For my time and inconvenience.
好了 快行动 行动!
That's it. Move, move!
第一分队 第二分队注意
Team one, team two, alpha bravo is exiting
目标正从建筑物后方逃离... 快行动
the rear of the building... move in.
快! 快!
Go! Go!
跟上! 跟着Jones!
Go! Follow Jones!
你没事吧?
You okay?
我们都没事
We're fine.
把他们带走
Arrest them.
带走他们 别让他们暴露了
Arrest them. We have to keep their cover.
戴上手铐 宣读条约 一切按规矩走
Handcuff them. Read them their rights, everything.
你们俩去北边 和Jones分开走!
You two are on the north end, opposite side of Jones!
快!
Go!
他们在哪?
Where are they?
在楼群中跑了
They disappeared between the buildings.
有人看到他们吗?
Anyone have eyes?
没有
Negative.
我们只找到了这个
All we got is this.
什么?
What?
他们换衣服了 真可恶!
Ah, they switched clothes. Damn it!
你参与的任务都这么好玩吗?
Are things always this interesting when you're around?
过来吧
Come on.
你被捕了
You're under arrest.
你弄丢了十万美金 他们有多生气?
So, how upset were they that you lost the 100 grand?
"生气"这个词都不足以形容了
"Upset" is a bit of an understatement.
他们已经开始了针对我的行政调查
It started an administrative inquiry.
不过只要我能把钱找回来就没事了...
Everything will be fine if I recover it...
还是等我找回来再说吧
when I recover it.
好吧 幸好钱不是Neal拿的
Well, the good news is Neal didn't take it.
是啊
Yeah.
算是有点进步
This is progress.
你觉得他和这事有什么关系吗?
Do you think he actually had anything to do with it?
没有 但是Neal这个人...
No, but the thing about Neal...
我从来都看不清他的真实面目
nothing is ever what it seems.
他本来就是个矛盾体
The guy's a contradiction.
一边对Kate不能自拔
He's obsessed about Kate,
另一边又和
But you should have seen him
遇到的女人打情骂俏
flirting with this girl at the takedown.
亲爱的 Neal就是这样的人
Well, honey, that's who Neal is.
本性难移嘛
That's never gonna change.
所以我才这么爱你
That's what I love about you so much.
怎么 结婚之后我就不会勾搭女人了吗?
What, that I lost all ability to flirt when we got married?
- 亲爱的 结婚之前你也不太会  - 那倒是
- Honey, it was even questionable then.  - It was
那个女孩是谁?
Who's the new girl?
她叫Taryn Vandersant
Taryn Vandersant.
我不认识她
Don't know her.
她是Lambert画廊的顾客
She's a buyer at the Lambert gallery.
挺漂亮的 看起来人也不错
She's beautiful, seems nice.
如果Neal喜欢的话 你应该鼓励鼓励他
Well, if Neal's interested, you should encourage it.
鼓励他? 我疯了吧
Encourage it? Oh, I need that like a hole in the head.
亲爱的 要是他能爱上另外一个女孩
Honey, if he would fall for the new girl,
说不定就真的不会再去找Kate了呢
he might actually stop chasing Kate.
- 爱你  - 我也爱你
- Love you.  - Love you.
昨天你和Taryn相处得不错嘛
You and Taryn were getting along pretty good yesterday.
她不是我的菜
She's not my type.
什么? 不是你的... 为什么不是你喜欢的类型?
What? Not your... why isn't she your type?
她喜欢艺术
She loves art.
她看起来就像是穿着卡其色衣服的劳拉・克劳馥(古墓丽影中角色)
She looks like Lara Croft in khakis.
是吗? 她是不是还给孤儿们烤饼干?
Really? Does she bake cookies for orphans, too?
是啊
She does.
我懂了
I get it.
要是我遇到喜欢的女孩 也许就能安定下来
Meet a nice girl, maybe settle down.
我就能省点心了 你也一样
Simplify my life, probably save yours.
你在饼干的事上肯定没说实话
You're lying about the cookies.
你怎么证明
Prove it.
那人是谁?
Who's that?
钱宁博物馆的馆长
Curator from the Channing Museum.
什么?
What?
他... 他来这干嘛?
Why... why is he here?
为了豪斯滕伯格那幅画来的 他说那幅画是他们馆藏的
The Haustenberg. He says it belongs to them.
把帽子摘了
Lose the stupid hat.
这幅画丢失的时候 钱宁博物馆为什么没有上报?
How come the Channing didn't report it missing?
当时我们确实上报了 不过那是在1967年
We did report it, when it was stolen in 1967.
我有个问题
I have a question.
画是在67年被偷的
The painting was stolen in '67,
那为什么失踪艺术品登记处的名录上没有它
but it's not listed on the art-loss registry.
那个登记处是1990年才建立的
The registry was established in 1990.
其实是91年
'91, actually.
你可以重新登记的
You could have re-filed the claim.
不好意思 你是哪位?
I'm sorry. You are who?
Neal Caffrey 他是我们的艺术顾问
Neal Caffrey. He's one of our art consultants.
叫Caffrey啊
Caffrey.
我可没听说过这个人
Not familiar with that name.
幸好你没听说过
It's probably for the best.
你是研究豪斯滕伯格作品的专家?
You're an expert on Haustenberg?
我了解近代欧洲后印象派的所有画家
All the late European post-impressionists.
"戴项链的年轻女孩"进馆时
I authenticated "young girl with locket" myself
是我亲自做的鉴定
when it first entered our collection.
的确是杰出的作品
You'll agree it's an excellent work,
我觉得这画过于伤感了
a bit sentimental for my taste,
很显然是受到了马蒂斯的影响
but the Matisse influence is apparent.
哦 鉴于马蒂斯是野兽派
Oh, well, considering Matisse was a Fauvist,
你这么说我无法赞同
I wouldn't agree with that at all.
除非你是在说他的早期作品
Unless you're talking about his early work,
我觉得你肯定没关注过 如果关注过 你那么说就大错特错了
which I don't think you are, and if you are, you're just wrong.
我们有理由相信
We have reason to believe that
它在一次入室抢劫中丢失了
this was taken in a residential robbery.
我并不关心这幅画
What happened to the painting
从我的博物馆丢失以后的去向
when it was taken from my museum is not my concern.
现在有人想买回被窃之物
Now, someone elected to buy stolen property.
我认为那也是犯罪
I believe that is a crime.
你知不知道豪斯腾伯格这幅画
Do you know how the Haustenberg
是怎么到你祖母手里的?
came into your grandmother's possession?
她在战后从匈牙利
She brought it with her from Hungary
来到这座城市时就带着它了
when she came to this country after the war.
怎么了?
Why?
Burke探员 打扰一下
Agent Burke, got a question for you.
好的
Yeah.
请原谅
Excuse me.
好好表现 小子
Play nice, kids.
这是怎么了?
What's going on?
你不擅长撒谎啊
You're not a very good liar.
那幅画是你祖母偷来的
Your grandmother stole the painting.
你为什么这么说?
Why would you say that?
她从未给这幅画买过保险
She never had it insured.
这是线索一
That was my first clue.
你俩这是在表演红脸白脸吗?
Is this like a good-cop, bad-cop thing?
他去接电话 你来搞怀柔
He takes a call. You wink at me.
就算我们拿回那幅画 也要还给钱宁博物馆
If we get the painting, it's going back to the Channing,
除非你给我个合适的理由不让他们拿回去
Unless you give us a good reason to keep it away from them.
行了 跟我说说吧
All right. Tell me a story.
她是怎么弄到画的?
How did she take it?
假设一下就好
Just... hypothetically.
假设?
Hypothetically?
小黑裙 一瓶系着蕾丝带的威士忌
A little black dress, a laced bottle of whiskey,
还有一个好色的爱尔兰保安
and a horny Irish security guard.
她干嘛要那么做?
Why'd she do it?
这是画里的吊坠
That's the locket.
你祖母就是画里的小女孩
Your grandmother's the little girl in the painting.
情况怎么样?
How's it going in there?
呃 还好吧
Oh, it's... it's fine.
- 找到Dorsett了吗?  - 没有
- Any luck on Dorsett? - No.
想像一下你怀揣十万美元和那幅画
Assuming you just walked with 100 grand in cash
你会怎么做?
and the painting, what do you do?
躲起来等风头过去
Go to ground till things cool off.
你会躲在哪里?
Where do you go?
Dorsett说过他有个女朋友
Dorsett said something about having a girlfriend.
- Brigitte  - 没错
- Brigitte. - Yeah.
昨晚有多少叫Brigitte的法国人入境?
How many Brigittes came in from France last night?
包括中间名和拼写变化的
Accounting for middle names and spelling variations,
比我想象中多得多
a lot more than I thought.
嗯 可以忽略中转航班的
Well, we can discount connecting flights.
以及50岁以上的
And women over 50.
告诉我我错了
Tell me I'm wrong.
嗯 这就剩下七个了
Well, that leaves seven.
很好
All right.
好了 弄些人手来 一组盯一个Brigitte
So, let's pull in some teams, and everybody take a Brigitte.
我们... 我们盯那个住在甘斯沃尔特的(以艳遇著名的酒店)
We'll...  we'll take the girl staying at the Gansevoort.
要是我就会住那里
That's where I'd stay.
为什么不用卫星什么的处理这种事
You'd think they'd have a satellite for things like this.
卫星能告诉我们的只有一点
The only thing a satellite is gonna tell us
他没在屋顶上
is that he's not on the roof.
这是传统方法
This is old-school.
"传统方法"
"Old-school".
你放松点好吗?
Will you relax?
你常冥想吗?
You meditate?
- 没有啊  - 真的?
- No.  - Really?
你这样子好像常冥想的样子
You look like a guy who meditates.
三明治?
Sandwich?
什么味道啊?
What is that smell?
辣味烤火腿
That's deviled ham.
- 不要!  - 尝点
- No!  - Come on.
不!
No!
不 别 调回去听比赛
No. Wait. Go back to the game.
不 这是我点的
No, I called it.
你不过是按按钮而已 那不叫点歌
You were just touching the buttons. That's not calling it.
能不这么孩子气吗?
What are we, 12?
也许吧
I guess we are.
如果这是你的车 我们就听你选的台
When we're in your car, we can listen to your station.
我没车
I don't have a car.
可悲的人生之路
Poor life choice.
还是听比赛
And we got the game.
你觉你能负担得起在那消费吗?
What do you think you can afford in that place?
给我20块
Spot me a $20.
干嘛不用你的新信用卡 金卡嘛?
Why don't you use your new gold card to get it?
你怎么知道的?
You know about that?
留着吧 可以让我掌握你都买了些什么东西
Keep it. It makes it easier for me to know what you're buying.
喔
Oh.
好吧 去吧 别耍花样
All right, go, but no Shenanigans.
十分钟 手机开着
You've got 10 minutes. And keep your phone on.
送给你的
That's for you.
打扰一下
你们讲法语吗?
可以请你们喝一杯吗?
Can I buy you a drink?
嘿!
Hey!
怎么?
What?
你觉得怎么样?
What do you think?
妓女吗?
Hookers?
不是
No.
那是Brigitte和她的朋友
That's Brigitte and her friend.
我说服她们带我们去她们那儿
I convinced them to invite us up to their suite.
Brigitte喜欢我 Claire是你的
Brigitte likes me. You can have Claire.
你疯了吧?
Are you completely out of your mind?
房间是以她的名义订的
The room is rented in her name.
她请我们去 这又不违法
We're not breaking any laws if she invites us in.
十万美元和那幅画说不定就在那里呢
The 100 grand and the painting could be inside.
你难道不想知道
Wouldn't you like to know
我们盯的这个到底是不是她吗?
if we're sitting in the right place?
对
Yeah.
哪个是Claire?
Which one's Claire?
好
Ah, oui.
Claire很可爱
Claire's cute.
没错 现在她就是此时此刻我最需要的
Yeah. She's exactly what I need in my life right now.
好了 没发现男式袜子
All right. There are no men's socks lying around.
Brigitte看来一点都不担心
Brigitte does not look like a girl
男朋友突然回来
who's worried about her boyfriend coming home.
Peter 你淡定点
Peter, you have to relax.
如果是找错了人 很快就会知道的
If we have the wrong Brigitte, we'll know soon enough.
回到车里去 继续吃辣味火腿
Beats sitting in the car, eating deviled ham.
好吧 好的
All right, fine.
一旦发现Dorsett住在这里
The second we find out if Dorsett is staying here,
我们马上离开 我来呼叫增援
we leave, and we call in reinforcements.
没问题
Done.
她们来了
They're coming.
嗯
Hmm.
喝一点?
Voil?
谢谢 非常感谢
Merci. Ah, merci beaucoup.
她不想让我们进那间屋
She doesn't want us in there.
没错 我看到她把门锁上了
Yeah, I saw her lock the door.
卫生间肯定还有个门
I bet there's a door in the bathroom
通向主卧的
that connects to the master suite.
我能打开
I can open it.
不 不行
No, you can't.
- 我谁也不说  - 不行
- I won't tell anyone. - No, no.
你知道规矩的
You understand the rules here.
听着 这我知道
Listen, I've heard the speech.
什么?
What's that?
她们想玩"输了脱"游戏
They want to play strip poker.
噢...
Oh...
开玩笑的
I'm kidding.
但你幻想一下啊 多美妙?
But could you imagine?
她们要来点音乐 对吧?
They want music, all right?
- 来吧 放松点  - 好吧
- Come on. Relax. - All right.
在那边呢 去吧
It's over there. Come on.
哦
Ooh.
稍等片刻
Just un moment.
Neal 我知道你想干嘛!
Neal, I know what you're doing!
稍等片刻
Just un moment.
别用法语说废话! 出来!
Cut the French crap! Get out here!
吸引她们的注意
Keep them occupied.
我没法吸引她们注意力!
I can't keep them occupied!
我不会... 说法语!
I don't... speak French!
哇
Whoa.
喔!
Whoo!
知道吗? 我必须起来了
You know what? I should get up right now.
我... 我做不到... 不行...
I... I can't... I can't do...
葡萄不错
That's a good grape.
啊!
Aah!
噢! 没事... 是手机响
Oh! It's just... It's just my phone.
我的手机
Just my phone.
别怕 我拿一下手机
No, I'm just getting my phone.
只是拿一下手机
I'm just getting it. That's all I'm doing.
拿一下我的... 看到没?
Just getting my... see?
不!
No!
不! 请别这样!
No! Please don't!
让我... 让我接电话
Let's... let me have the phone.
把电话给我!
Give me the phone!
谢谢
Thank you.
天啊 是El!
Oh, God, it's El!
嗨
Hello.
哦 嘿 我以为你不会接的
Oh, hey. I didn't think I was gonna get you.
我只是给你留个信儿
I was actually gonna leave a message.
嗯 是呀 好的
Oh, hi. Yeah. Well.
看到是你打来的当然要接了 怎么了?
Uh, saw that it was you. What's up?
没事 刚和客户吃完晚餐回来
Nothing. I just got back from a client dinner.
我想知道监视工作怎么样啦
I wanted to see how the stakeout was going.
有突破性进展
Having a blast.
你在哪啊?
Where are you?
我在... 我在...
I'm at a... I'm at a...
在夜店?
Are you at a nightclub?
没错 就是在夜店
Yes, that's where I am.
我们... 我们... 就是在夜店
We... we... we're at a nightclub.
我们...我们跟踪他到了夜店
We... we followed him into a nightclub.
在甘斯沃尔特?
At the Gansevoort?
亲爱的 真棒
Wow, honey. I'm impressed.
真没想到你到那儿去了
I can't believe you got in there.
说来话长 El
It's a long story, El.
El 我得走了 这里有点状况 好吗?
El, I've got to go. I've got a situation here, okay?
我爱你 亲爱的!
I love you, honey!
我爱你 这人很多
I love you. It's crowded.
有点乱
It's crowded.
嘿 Neal Caffrey!
Hey, Neal. Caffrey!
Caffrey 我们... Caffrey!
Caffrey, we got... Caffrey!
哦!
Oh!
"致最亲爱的Julianna 请永远留着它"
"to my dearest Julianna, keep this forever."
我来跟Elizabeth谈吧 行吗? 让我弥补一下
Let me talk to Elizabeth, all right? It's the least I can do.
不 真想弥补就什么都别做
No, the least you can do is nothing,
必须什么都别做
which is exactly what you will do.
都是我的错
It's my fault.
不 我不许你骗我妻子
No, I don't need you to lie to my wife.
你要自己骗她?
You gonna do it yourself?
不
No.
真相 Peter
The truth, Peter.
- 很冒险啊  - 假设一下...
- Bold choice. - Hypothetically ...
听着 我来跟他说我一直不停抱怨你的车
See, I would tell her that I wouldn't stop complaining about the car,
所以你就让我到夜店里去了
so you let me go into the nightclub,
你看到了嫌犯在我后面进去了
and you witnessed the suspect enter after me
只有跟过来
and had no choice but to follow.
跟事实差不多
It's almost the truth.
总比离婚要好
It's better than alimony.
是
Yeah.
我们跟丢了Dorsett
We lost Dorsett.
糟糕...
God...
画和现金呢?
What about the painting and the cash?
都不见了
All gone.
Dorsett逃跑了
Dorsett escaped.
糟糕了
This is bad.
对 是很糟糕
Yeah, this is bad.
现在可能真成问题了 EL
You know, this one may be a real problem, El.
所以要是你找不到Dorsett
So, if you don't find Dorsett,
Neal怎么办?
what happens to Neal?
他完了 重新回去坐牢
He's done. He's back inside.
你觉得他真的偷了画吗?
Do you actually think he stole it?
嗯
Yeah.
你没事吧?
You gonna be okay?
我... 我没事 嗯
Yeah, I'll be... I'll be fine, yeah.
亲爱的 听我说
Honey, listen.
昨晚在酒店的事...
About last night at the hotel...
你说夜店吧
You mean the nightclub.
对对
Yeah.
呃...
Well...
Neal 在抱怨我的三明治
Neal was complaining about my sandwich,
然后他就开始摆弄收音机 所以我...
and then he started fidgeting with the radio, so I ...
其实我们没去夜店
there was no nightclub.
我明白
I know.
亲爱的 你觉得做夫妻都10多年了 我会不知道...
Honey, you don't think after 10 years I know when you're...
我在夸大事实吗?
Stretching the truth?
呃 这样也算吧
Well, that's a nice way of putting it.
下次可以直接告诉我
Next time, just tell me.
我跟Neal就这么说的
That's what I told Neal.
那继续保持
Then stick to it.
我会的
I will.
我知道你是好男人
I know you're a good man.
她好看吗?
Was she cute?
这个得看你怎么想了
Well, now, that depends on your definition,
因为我现在不想再说这事了
'cause I... I got to plead the fifth on this one.
那好吧
Yeah, okay.
你是哪位?
Who is this?
我得问你才对
I could ask you the same thing.
你好像有不少名字 George
You seem to have many names, George.
你是Dorsett
Dorsett.
你从哪弄到号码的?
How'd you get this number?
你用信用卡给我女朋友买了杯酒
You bought my girlfriend a drink with your credit card.
你的足智多谋让我印象很深刻
I'm impressed with your resourcefulness.
现在让你见识见识我的本事了 我要那幅画
Now you will see mine. I want the painting.
如果没还回来的话
If it is not returned,
Joshua会去画廊好好拜访一下你的漂亮女友
Joshua will pay a visit to your beautiful friend at the gallery.
你别把她扯进来
You leave her out of this.
Brigitte本无牵连 但你把她扯进来了
Brigitte was out of bounds, yet you involved her.
你制定了规则
You set the rules.
那你就得照着来玩
Now you must play by them.
给我两天
I need two days.
你只有两天时间
That's all you have.
你偷了那幅画?
You stole the painting?
我打算还给Julianna
I was going to give it back to Julianna.
你怎么这么孩子气... 不考虑后果
You're like a child... No sense of consequence.
好吧 你看到这里的题字吗?
Okay. Will you look at the inscription?
钱宁馆长说他在这幅画被偷之前
The Channing curator said he authenticated the painting
就验过了
before it was stolen.
他看到了这幅画该归Julianna
He saw that it belonged to Julianna
但却视而不见
and chose to ignore it.
所以你就来做罗宾汉
And you're Robin Hood.
我有没有忘了告诉你
And did I forget to mention the part
是你"偷"了这幅画啊?!
where you stole the painting?!
我没料到Dorsett会逃跑
I didn't think Dorsett would get away.
那是因为你不喜欢博物馆里的人
This is because you don't like the guy from the Channing.
你因为有成见才这么做
You did this for spite.
我尽量克制自己了
I've done things for less.
我不能让他去骚扰Taryn
I can't let him go after Taryn.
那你要怎么做?
So, what are you gonna do?
最好是好消息
This better be good.
我拿了那幅画
I took the painting.
该死 Neal
Damn it, Neal.
我没打算...
I wasn't gonna...
我是为...
I did it for...
我能用它抓来Dorsett 他不知道我替你干活
I can use it to catch Dorsett. He doesn't know I work for you.
我们明天再说
We'll set it up tomorrow.
现在从我家滚出去
Now get the hell out of my house.
好的
Okay.
再见 Elisabeth
Good night Elisabeth.
拜拜 Neal
Bye, Neal.
呃 他...
Well, he, uh...
跟你说了偷画的事实
told you the truth about the painting.
嗯 因为他们拿Taryn来威胁他
Mm-hmm. Because they threatened Taryn.
这是个开始
It's a start.
嗯
Yeah.
的确是个开始
It's a start.
你知道你完全无法克制冲动
You know you have absolutely no impulse control.
把鹅黄的颜料给我
Hand me the Naples yellow.
豪斯腾伯格的笔法非常流畅
Haustenberg's brushwork is much more fluid.
但你的却坑坑洼洼的
You're being choppy.
哪有 我的笔法没问题
Nah. My brushwork's fine.
这是可以骗过普通游客
This could trick the occasional tourist,
但钱宁博物馆馆长可不是等闲之辈
but this guy at the Channing will not be fooled.
我相信他不是
I'm sure he won't.
这颜料要做旧
This pigment needs to be aged.
我去加热烤箱
I'll go preheat the oven.
- 125度  - 明白 明白
- It's 125.  - Yeah, yeah, yeah.
我知道怎么给画做旧
I know how to age a painting.
我的缓刑还靠谱吗?
How tenuous is my probation?
很难说
It's pretty thin.
就看这次了
We need this one.
很简单 对吧?
It's simple, right?
对 所以别搞复杂了
Yeah, so don't make it complicated.
快点把Dorsett拿下
Take Dorsett down quickly.
要是我抓到他 你会再相信我吗?
If I get him, you trust me again?
是的 同志
Yeah, comrade.
你还要再验证?
You still gonna verify?
嗯 对
Oh, yeah.
到了
Here we go.
真了不起你还有胆子自己来
Surprised you had the guts to come yourself.
这不是胆量
It's not bravery.
Joshua带着一幅一百万美元的画我不放心
I simply don't trust Joshua with a million-dollar painting.
这样活着不容易吧?
Is it hard to live like that,
连最亲近的人都不敢相信
not trusting the people closest to you?
大概吧 但钱归我了
I suppose, but I'll take the money.
你赢了
You won.
对啊 是个好游戏
Yes, but it was a good game.
联邦调查局! 你被捕了!
FBI! You're under arrest!
把手举起来让我们看见! 把画给我!
Hands where I can see them! Give me the painting!
豪斯腾伯格是她的父亲
Haustenberg was her father.
对
Yes.
她是他的私生女
She was his illegitimate daughter,
但他其实在匈牙利有家室了
but he had a family then in Hungary.
在战争开始之前
It was before the war.
那这为何最后到了钱宁博物馆手里?
How did the painting end up at the Channing?
他遗嘱里说把画给我祖母
He willed the painting to my grandmother,
但他死后 博物馆对他的遗嘱视而不见
but when he died, the museum chose to ignore his will.
谁会在乎一个著名画家的私生女啊?
Who cares about the illegitimate daughter of a famous artist?
有钱人偷了也不能说偷
It's not theft when rich men do it.
你怎么知道钱宁博物馆的人
How do you know that the Channing
不会再要回去呢?
won't try to take it back again?
要是他们会的话 馆长就要解释
Because if they do, the curator will have to explain
为什么博物馆要违背豪斯腾伯格的遗愿
why the museum went against Haustenberg's wishes,
但... 我觉得他不会这样做
and... I don't think he wants that.
Neal 你到底做什么了?
Neal, what have you done?
我亲爱的Walter 我知道你上次看到了什么 NC
有问题吗?
Problem?
没有没有
No, no.
只是突然觉得...
Just, uh, overcome with the, uh...
能看到Haustenberg的原著归其所属
I'm thrilled to have the original Haustenberg
我非常激动
back where it belongs.
偷偷出来幽会
Forbidden romantic meetings
是一件私事 Moz
are kind of a personal thing, Moz.
嗯 说得好像我会让你一个人来一样
Yeah, like I was gonna let you come alone.
万一是戴戒指的人放的纸条呢?
What if the guy with the ring planted that note?
他不会的
He didn't.
当你额头上出现红色光点时
You'll be happy I came
你就会高兴多亏我来了
when a red laser dot suddenly appears on your forehead.
别再装英雄了
Enough with the hero talk.
- Kate留下了纸条  - 好吧
- Kate left the note.  - Okay.
也许她三天前写的
Maybe she wrote it three days ago
也可能是三个月前写的
or maybe three months ago.
她会来的
She'll be here.
今天是星期五
Well, it is Friday,
已经中午了 那她在哪?
and it was noon, so where is she?
- Kate?  - 喂 Neal?
- Kate?  - Neal?
Kate 你在哪?
Kate, where are you?
我没有很多时间
I don't have a lot of time.
你在这
You're here.
Neal 还在听吗?
Neal, are you still there?
听着 Neal
Neal.
嗨
Hi.
- 呆着别动 我马上过去...  - 不 Neal
- Stay there. I'm coming...  - No, Neal.
Neal 他就在附近
Neal, he's close.
- 戴戒指的男人?  - 对
- The man with the ring?  - Yes.
我不管
I don't care.
听着 我要你告诉我 你把所有东西都藏到哪了
Listen, I need you to tell me where you hid everything.
什么?
What?
钱 债券 艺术品... 所有东西
The money, the bonds, the art...  all of it.
怎么了?
Why?
他想样东西...
He wants something...
一样你偷了藏起来的东西
Something you took, something you hid.
我藏了不少东西
I hid a lot of things.
那你就全都给他
Well, then, give him everything.
要是他拿到了他想要的 他就会放我回到你身边了
If he gets what he wants, he'll let me come back to you.
他是谁?
Who is he?
我不能告诉你 对你来说太危险了
I can't tell you. It's too dangerous for you.
危险? 怎么这么说?
Dangerous? Why?
Kate 告诉我 我能保护你
Kate, just tell me. I can protect you.
你只有这样才能帮我
This is the only way you can help me.
你总是对我说要相信你
You always told me I had to trust you.
现在你要相信我
Well, now you have to trust me.
我想要回家
I want to come home.
拜托你就告诉我你把东西都藏哪了
Please just tell me where you hid everything.
不
No.
我想要回家
I want to come home.
这是我仅有的赌注了
It's the only leverage I got.
待在那 行吗? 我马上过去
Just stay there, okay? I'm coming up.
Neal! 等等!
Neal! Neal!
Kate吗?
Kate?
Mozzie 跟Neal说我爱他
Mozzie, tell Neal I love him.
告诉他这是唯一的方法
Tell him it's the only way.
嘿 Kate!
Kate!